ANDREA GEDRICH

Los Angeles, CA
andi.gedrich@gmail.com
www.andreagedrich.com | linkedin.com/andreagedrich
github.com/AndiGedrich
646-265-8160

I love solving problems, whether for users, clients or organizationally within a business. I believe there is nothing that cannot be solved or improved by digging into data, identifying trends, pain points and desired outcomes, converting them into hypotheses and testable features which can then be built, measured and optimized.

With 10 years of experience in the Digital Agency industry, spanning Project Management / Production, User Experience, Strategy and Operations, I have recently completed the 12 week General Assembly Web Development Immersive program in order to complete my hands-on knowledge of the full cycle of digital product development.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Leadership & Team Management
- Process Development
- Operational and Business Strategy
- Agile and Waterfall Methods of Production

- Business Requirements Discovery & Documentation
- User Experience Research, Wireframing | Prototyping
- Web Development Javascript | JQuery | HTML | CSS | Ruby on Rails | NodeJs | Angular | Express

EXPERIENCE

BLITZ Agency

VP, Operations & Finance | May 2015- November 2015

Sr. Director, Operations & Finance | October 2012 – April 2015

Operations Manager | February 2007 – May 2010

- Responsible for day to day operation of 100+ employee, 22m revenue agency including:
 - All financial reporting, revenue recognition, project and agency profitability;
 - O Human Resource Management, recruiting, agency culture and employee development;
 - External production vendor contracting, pricing and payment;
 - Management of 5 direct reports responsible for: Resource Management/Traffic, Office Management, AP/AR and
 HR.

- Accomplishments:
 - o Implemented financial controls which allowed the agency to profitably grow from 35 employees to 100 employees, ultimately resulting in the Agency's acquisition.

Experience Planner | June 2011 – September 2012

- Worked with clients including Hasbro, Mattel, the band U2, VIZIO and Disney to gather, research and discover business and
 audience requirements, providing easily consumable insights to internal and freelance creative and development teams in order
 to design and produce effective web/ mobile sites, games, apps, social and display ad media. Responsibilities included:
 - Conducting client stake-holder interviews and audience research, utilizing tools such as NPD, eMarketer, Forrester, and Mintel.
 - o Producing Strategic/ Creative Briefs, Business Requirements documentation, wireframes and development annotations.
 - Developing content management strategies and architecture for large volumes of multi-media assets including video, music, images, games and character activities.
- Accomplishments:
 - Identified a critical gap in the agency's capabilities, which was the bridge between the client's business needs and our digital development. My work in this area proved-out the need for the implementation and growth of our Strategy and Analytics disciplines.
 - Lead the strategy and insights development which resulted in the Agency's win of the Barbie.com and Hot Wheels
 Digital Strategy and development projects for Mattel.

Project Manager | May 2006 - February 2007

- Managed production teams to successfully design and build digital properties for clients such as Microsoft, General Electric,
 Disney and FOX Networks. Responsibilities included:
 - Scoping/ pricing and scheduling projects requiring orchestration between client, creative and technical development.
 - Ensuring delivery of projects on time and within budget while enabling the team to do its best work.

EDUCATION

Columbia University – B.A. History / B.A. Psychology

General Assembly – Web Development Immersive Program

Certificates

Cornell University Human Resources Management

Workamajig Brown Belt